<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.7.3">Jekyll</generator>
  
  
  <link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
  <link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
  <updated>2018-03-30T13:13:52+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://localhost:4000//</id>

  
    <title type="html">DecodeVector</title>
  

  

  
    <author>
        <name>Mathscapes Research</name>
      
      
    </author>
  

  
  
    <entry>
      
      <title type="html">Scoring and Level Guide</title>
      
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/03/28/scoring-guide/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Scoring and Level Guide" />
      <published>2018-03-28T00:04:08+05:30</published>
      <updated>2018-03-28T00:04:08+05:30</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/2018/03/28/scoring-guide</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/03/28/scoring-guide/">&lt;p&gt;Score can be calculated by&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script type=&quot;math/tex; mode=display&quot;&gt;D + P&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;where,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;$ D = S - \frac{T}{L} $ where, $S$ is the number of days you’ve solved at least one PSET problem, and $T$ is the total number of days since your date of join.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;$ P $ is the sum of points accumulated by solving PSET problems.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      
        <author>
            <name>Gaurav Singh</name>
          
          
        </author>
      

      
        <category term="Notes" />
      
        <category term="Important" />
      

      
        <category term="Scoring" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">Score can be calculated by</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
  
  
    <entry>
      
      <title type="html">Introduction to Python</title>
      
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/03/28/introduction-to-python/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Introduction to Python" />
      <published>2018-03-28T00:04:08+05:30</published>
      <updated>2018-03-28T00:04:08+05:30</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/2018/03/28/introduction-to-python</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/03/28/introduction-to-python/">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.python.org/downloads/&quot;&gt;Download Python&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://python.swaroopch.com/&quot;&gt;A Byte of Python&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.python.org/3/&quot;&gt;Python Official Documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      
        <author>
            <name>Gaurav Singh</name>
          
          
        </author>
      

      
        <category term="Resources" />
      

      
        <category term="Python" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">Download Python A Byte of Python Python Official Documentation</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
  
  
    <entry>
      
      <title type="html">Getting Started with p5.js</title>
      
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/03/28/getting-started-with-p5js/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Getting Started with p5.js" />
      <published>2018-03-28T00:04:08+05:30</published>
      <updated>2018-03-28T00:04:08+05:30</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/2018/03/28/getting-started-with-p5js</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/03/28/getting-started-with-p5js/">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://p5js.org/get-started/&quot;&gt;Get Started&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://p5js.org/download/&quot;&gt;Download p5.js Library&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://p5js.org/reference/&quot;&gt;Reference&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      
        <author>
            <name>Gaurav Singh</name>
          
          
        </author>
      

      
        <category term="Notes" />
      
        <category term="Resources" />
      

      
        <category term="p5.js" />
      
        <category term="Processing" />
      
        <category term="JavaScript" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">Get Started Download p5.js Library Reference</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
  
  
    <entry>
      
      <title type="html">Using GitHub</title>
      
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/03/27/using-github/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Using GitHub" />
      <published>2018-03-27T16:20:08+05:30</published>
      <updated>2018-03-27T16:20:08+05:30</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/2018/03/27/using-github</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/03/27/using-github/">&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-is-github&quot;&gt;What is GitHub?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=w3jLJU7DT5E&quot;&gt;What is GitHub? &lt;em&gt;(Video)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;getting-started&quot;&gt;Getting Started&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://try.github.io/levels/1/challenges/1&quot;&gt;Using GitHub&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://guides.github.com/introduction/flow/&quot;&gt;Understanding the GitHub Flow&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://guides.github.com/activities/hello-world/&quot;&gt;Hello World&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;more&quot;&gt;More&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://guides.github.com/features/issues/&quot;&gt;Mastering Issues&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://guides.github.com/features/mastering-markdown/&quot;&gt;Mastering Markdown&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      
        <author>
            <name>Gaurav Singh</name>
          
          
        </author>
      

      
        <category term="Notes" />
      
        <category term="Resources" />
      

      
        <category term="GitHub" />
      
        <category term="Git" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">What is GitHub? What is GitHub? (Video)</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
  
  
    <entry>
      
      <title type="html">Contributing to this website</title>
      
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/03/27/contributing-to-this-website/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Contributing to this website" />
      <published>2018-03-27T12:04:08+05:30</published>
      <updated>2018-03-27T12:04:08+05:30</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/2018/03/27/contributing-to-this-website</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/03/27/contributing-to-this-website/">&lt;p&gt;Send your posts (in &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;.markdown&lt;/code&gt; format) to &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:grv@mathscapes.xyz&quot;&gt;me&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;formatting-guide&quot;&gt;Formatting Guide&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://guides.github.com/features/mastering-markdown/&quot;&gt;Mastering Markdown&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://moser-isi.ethz.ch/docs/typeset_equations.pdf&quot;&gt;Typesetting Equations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikipedia:LaTeX_symbols&quot;&gt;LaTeX Symbols&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In case of any queries, create a issue &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mathscapes/DecodeVector/issues&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      
        <author>
            <name>Gaurav Singh</name>
          
          
        </author>
      

      
        <category term="Notes" />
      
        <category term="Important" />
      

      
        <category term="Markdown" />
      
        <category term="Latex" />
      
        <category term="Math" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">Send your posts (in .markdown format) to me.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
  
  
    <entry>
      
      <title type="html">Code of Conduct</title>
      
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/03/27/code-of-conduct/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Code of Conduct" />
      <published>2018-03-27T12:04:08+05:30</published>
      <updated>2018-03-27T12:04:08+05:30</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/2018/03/27/code-of-conduct</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/03/27/code-of-conduct/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;big&gt;This Code is not exhaustive or complete. It is not a rulebook; it serves to distil our common understanding of a collaborative, shared environment and goals. We expect it to be followed in spirit as much as in this document.&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This code of conduct outlines our expectations for participants within the DecodeVector community, as well as steps to reporting unacceptable behavior. We are committed to providing a welcoming and inspiring community for all and expect our code of conduct to be honored. Anyone who violates this code of conduct may be banned from the community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Morality cannot be legislated, but behavior can be regulated.”&lt;br /&gt;
– Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;our-decodevector-community-strives-to&quot;&gt;Our DecodeVector community strives to:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Be friendly and patient.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Be welcoming:&lt;/em&gt; We strive to be a community that welcomes and supports people of all backgrounds and identities. This includes, but is not limited to members of any race, ethnicity, culture, national origin, colour, immigration status, social and economic class, educational level, sex, sexual orientation, gender identity and expression, age, size, family status, political belief, religion, and mental and physical ability.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Be considerate:&lt;/em&gt; Your work will be used by other people, and you in turn will depend on the work of others. Any decision you take will affect other members, and you should take those consequences into account when making decisions.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Be respectful:&lt;/em&gt; Not all of us will agree all the time, but disagreement is no excuse for poor behavior and poor manners. We might all experience some frustration now and then, but we cannot allow that frustration to turn into a personal attack. It’s important to remember that a community where people feel uncomfortable or threatened is not a productive one.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Be careful in the words that we choose:&lt;/em&gt; we are a community of professionals, and we conduct ourselves professionally. Be kind to others. Do not insult or put down other members. Harassment and other exclusionary behavior aren’t acceptable.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Try to understand why we disagree:&lt;/em&gt; Disagreements, both social and technical, happen all the time. It is important that we resolve disagreements and differing views constructively. Remember that we’re different. The strength of our community comes from its diversity, people from a wide range of backgrounds. Different people have different perspectives on issues. Being unable to understand why someone holds a viewpoint doesn’t mean that they’re wrong. Don’t forget that it is human to err and blaming each other doesn’t get us anywhere. Instead, focus on helping to resolve issues and learning from mistakes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;leadership-authority-and-responsibility&quot;&gt;Leadership, authority and responsibility&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We all lead by example, in debate and in action. We encourage new members to feel empowered to lead, to take action, and to experiment when they feel innovation could improve the project. Leadership can be exercised by anyone simply by taking action, there is no need to wait for recognition when the opportunity to lead presents itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;delegation-from-the-top&quot;&gt;Delegation from the top&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Responsibility within DecodeVector starts with the “benevolent dictator”, who delegates specific responsibilities and the corresponding authority to a series of teams. Its delegated representative will arbitrate in any dispute.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We are a meritocracy&lt;/strong&gt;; we delegate decision making, organisation and leadership from senior bodies to the most able and engaged candidates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;we-value-discussion-data-and-decisiveness&quot;&gt;We value discussion, data and decisiveness&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We gather opinions, data and commitments from concerned parties before taking a decision. We expect leaders to help teams come to a decision in a reasonable time, to seek guidance or be willing to take the decision themselves when consensus is lacking, and to take responsibility for implementation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The poorest decision of all is no decision: clarity of direction has value in itself. Sometimes all the data are not available, or consensus is elusive. A decision must still be made. There is no guarantee of a perfect decision every time - we prefer to err, learn, and err less in future than to postpone action indefinitely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We recognise that the project works better when we trust the teams closest to a problem to make the decision for the project. If we learn of a decision that we disagree with, we can engage the relevant team to find common ground, and failing that, we have a governance structure that can review the decision. Ultimately, if a decision has been taken by the people responsible for it, and is supported by the DecodeVector, it will stand. None of us expects to agree with every decision, and we value highly the willingness to stand by the project and help it deliver even on the occasions when we ourselves may prefer a different route.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;teamwork&quot;&gt;Teamwork&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A leader’s foremost goal is the success of the team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“A virtuoso is judged by their actions; a leader is judged by the actions of their team.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A leader knows when to act and when to step back. They know when to delegate work, and when to take it upon themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;credit&quot;&gt;Credit&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A good leader does not seek the limelight, but celebrates team members for the work they do. Leaders may be more visible than members of the team, good ones use that visibility to highlight the great work of others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;courage-and-considerateness&quot;&gt;Courage and considerateness&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leadership occasionally requires bold decisions that will not be widely understood, agreed by everyone or popular. We value the courage to take such decisions, because they enable the DecodeVector as a whole to move forward faster than we could if we required complete consensus. Nevertheless, boldness demands considerateness; take bold decisions, but do so mindful of the challenges they present for others, and work to soften the impact of those decisions on them. Communicating changes and their reasoning clearly and early on is as important as the implementation of the change itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;conflicts-of-interest&quot;&gt;Conflicts of interest&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We expect leaders to be aware when they are conflicted due to personal schedule or other projects they are involved in, and abstain or delegate decisions that may be seen to be self-interested. We expect that everyone who participates in DecodeVector does so with the goal of progress of DecodeVector.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When in doubt, ask for a second opinion. Perceived conflicts of interest are important to address; as a leader, act to ensure that decisions are credible even if they must occasionally be unpopular, difficult or favourable to the interests of one group over another.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;diversity-statement&quot;&gt;Diversity Statement&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We encourage everyone to participate and are committed to building a community for all. Although we will fail at times, we seek to treat everyone both as fairly and equally as possible. Whenever a member has made a mistake, we expect them to take responsibility for it. If someone has been harmed or offended, it is our responsibility to listen carefully and respectfully, and do our best to right the wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although this list cannot be exhaustive, we explicitly honor diversity in age, gender, gender identity or expression, culture, ethnicity, language, national origin, political beliefs, profession, race, religion, sexual orientation, socioeconomic status, and technical ability. We will not tolerate discrimination based on any of the protected characteristics above, including participants with disabilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;attribution--acknowledgements&quot;&gt;Attribution &amp;amp; Acknowledgements&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This document uses portions from &lt;a href=&quot;http://todogroup.org/opencodeofconduct/&quot;&gt;Open Code of Conduct by TODO Group&lt;/a&gt; and is inspired from other communities and projects – &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.djangoproject.com/conduct/reporting/&quot;&gt;Django&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.python.org/community/diversity/&quot;&gt;Python&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ubuntu.com/community/code-of-conduct&quot;&gt;Ubuntu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.contributor-covenant.org/&quot;&gt;Contributor Covenant&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://geekfeminism.org/about/code-of-conduct/&quot;&gt;Geek Feminism&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://citizencodeofconduct.org/&quot;&gt;Citizen Code of Conduct&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our Code of Conduct is licensed under &lt;a href=&quot;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/&quot;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution-Share Alike 3.0 license&lt;/a&gt; and you may re-use it for your own community, and modify it as you wish, just please allow others to use your modifications and give credit to the DecodeVector and all the above organisations/projects!&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      
        <author>
            <name>Gaurav Singh</name>
          
          
        </author>
      

      
        <category term="Notes" />
      
        <category term="Important" />
      

      

      
        <summary type="html">This Code is not exhaustive or complete. It is not a rulebook; it serves to distil our common understanding of a collaborative, shared environment and goals. We expect it to be followed in spirit as much as in this document.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
  
  
    <entry>
      
      <title type="html">[PASCT] Pascal’s Triangle</title>
      
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/02/09/pset-pasct/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="[PASCT] Pascal's Triangle" />
      <published>2018-02-09T14:30:08+05:30</published>
      <updated>2018-02-09T14:30:08+05:30</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/2018/02/09/pset-pasct</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/02/09/pset-pasct/">&lt;p&gt;In mathematics, Pascal’s triangle is a triangular array of the binomial coefficients. The rows of Pascal’s triangle are conventionally enumerated starting with row $n = 0$ at the top (the $0$ th row). The entries in each row are numbered from the left beginning with $k = 0$ and are usually staggered relative to the numbers in the adjacent rows. The triangle may be constructed in the following manner: In row $0$ (the topmost row), there is a unique nonzero entry $1$. Each entry of each subsequent row is constructed by adding the number above and to the left with the number above and to the right, treating blank entries as $0$. For example, the initial number in the first (or any other) row is $1$ (the sum of $0$ and $1$), whereas the numbers $1$ and $3$ in the third row are added to produce the number $4$ in the fourth row.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read a number $N$ in a Python program and print $N$ lines of Pascal’s triangle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pascal%27s_triangle#/media/File:Pascal_triangle_small.png&quot;&gt;View Pascal’s Triangle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      
        <author>
            <name>Gaurav Singh</name>
          
          
        </author>
      

      
        <category term="Pset" />
      
        <category term="1-Point" />
      

      
        <category term="Python" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">In mathematics, Pascal’s triangle is a triangular array of the binomial coefficients. The rows of Pascal’s triangle are conventionally enumerated starting with row $n = 0$ at the top (the $0$ th row). The entries in each row are numbered from the left beginning with $k = 0$ and are usually staggered relative to the numbers in the adjacent rows. The triangle may be constructed in the following manner: In row $0$ (the topmost row), there is a unique nonzero entry $1$. Each entry of each subsequent row is constructed by adding the number above and to the left with the number above and to the right, treating blank entries as $0$. For example, the initial number in the first (or any other) row is $1$ (the sum of $0$ and $1$), whereas the numbers $1$ and $3$ in the third row are added to produce the number $4$ in the fourth row.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
  
  
    <entry>
      
      <title type="html">[SHRM1] Simple Harmonic Motion</title>
      
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/02/09/pset-shrm1/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="[SHRM1] Simple Harmonic Motion" />
      <published>2018-02-09T14:30:08+05:30</published>
      <updated>2018-02-09T14:30:08+05:30</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/2018/02/09/pset-shrm1</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/02/09/pset-shrm1/">&lt;p&gt;In mechanics and physics, simple harmonic motion is a special type of periodic motion or oscillation motion where the restoring force is directly proportional to the displacement and acts in the direction opposite to that of displacement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simple harmonic motion can serve as a mathematical model for a variety of motions, such as the oscillation of a spring. In addition, other phenomena can be approximated by simple harmonic motion, including the motion of a simple pendulum as well as molecular vibration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sketch as shown in this &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Simple_harmonic_motion#/media/File:Simple_Harmonic_Motion_Orbit.gif&quot;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt; through P5JS program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can display text in P5JS by using text() function.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-javascript highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;text&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;text-to-display&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;x&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;y&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      
        <author>
            <name>Gaurav Singh</name>
          
          
        </author>
      

      
        <category term="Pset" />
      
        <category term="1-Point" />
      

      
        <category term="Kinematics" />
      
        <category term="p5.js" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">In mechanics and physics, simple harmonic motion is a special type of periodic motion or oscillation motion where the restoring force is directly proportional to the displacement and acts in the direction opposite to that of displacement.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
  
  
    <entry>
      
      <title type="html">[FACT1] Factorial</title>
      
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/02/08/pset-fact1/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="[FACT1] Factorial" />
      <published>2018-02-08T14:30:08+05:30</published>
      <updated>2018-02-08T14:30:08+05:30</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/2018/02/08/pset-fact1</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/02/08/pset-fact1/">&lt;p&gt;Write a computer program to read an integer N and print its factorial.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;test-case&quot;&gt;Test Case&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Input:&lt;/em&gt; 3&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Output:&lt;/em&gt; 6&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://p5js.org/examples/dom-input-and-button.html&quot;&gt;How to read an input in p5.js?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-is-factorial&quot;&gt;What is Factorial?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In mathematics, the factorial of a non-negative integer $n$, denoted by $n!$, is the product of all positive integers less than or equal to $n$. For example,
image&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script type=&quot;math/tex; mode=display&quot;&gt;5! = 5 \times 4 \times 3 \times 2 \times 1 = 120&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The value of $0!$ is $1$, according to the convention for an empty product.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      
        <author>
            <name>Gaurav Singh</name>
          
          
        </author>
      

      
        <category term="Pset" />
      
        <category term="1-Point" />
      

      
        <category term="p5.js" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">Write a computer program to read an integer N and print its factorial.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
  
  
    <entry>
      
      <title type="html">[ADDR3] 4-Bit Full Adder</title>
      
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/02/07/pset-addr3/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="[ADDR3] 4-Bit Full Adder" />
      <published>2018-02-07T14:30:08+05:30</published>
      <updated>2018-02-07T14:30:08+05:30</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/2018/02/07/pset-addr3</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/02/07/pset-addr3/">&lt;p&gt;Design a 4-bit full adder.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      
        <author>
            <name>Gaurav Singh</name>
          
          
        </author>
      

      
        <category term="Pset" />
      
        <category term="1-Point" />
      

      
        <category term="Logic-Gates" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">Design a 4-bit full adder.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
  
  
    <entry>
      
      <title type="html">[FUNC1] Functions</title>
      
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/02/06/pset-func1/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="[FUNC1] Functions" />
      <published>2018-02-06T14:30:08+05:30</published>
      <updated>2018-02-06T14:30:08+05:30</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/2018/02/06/pset-func1</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/02/06/pset-func1/">&lt;p&gt;In mathematics, a function is a relation between a set of inputs and a set of permissible outputs with a property that each input related to exactly one output. An example is a function that relates to each real number $x$ to its square $x^2$. The output of a function $f$ corresponding to an input $x$ is denoted by $f(x)$ (read as “$f$ of $x$”). In this example, if the input is $-3$, then the output is $9$, and we may write $f(-3)=0$. The input variable(s) are sometimes referred to as the argument(s) of the function.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zero of function, also called as root, of a real-, complex- or generally vector-valued function $f$ is a member $x$ of the domain of $f$ such that $f(x)$ vanishes at $x$; that is&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;$x$ such that $f(x) = 0$&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Find at least one zero for each of the following functions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;$ f(x) = x^2 - x + 1 $&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;$ f(x) = x^2 - \sqrt{x} $&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;$ f(x) = x^2 - 20x $&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;$ f(x,y) = x^2 + y^2 - 2xy $&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      
        <author>
            <name>Gaurav Singh</name>
          
          
        </author>
      

      
        <category term="Pset" />
      
        <category term="1-Point" />
      

      

      
        <summary type="html">In mathematics, a function is a relation between a set of inputs and a set of permissible outputs with a property that each input related to exactly one output. An example is a function that relates to each real number $x$ to its square $x^2$. The output of a function $f$ corresponding to an input $x$ is denoted by $f(x)$ (read as “$f$ of $x$”). In this example, if the input is $-3$, then the output is $9$, and we may write $f(-3)=0$. The input variable(s) are sometimes referred to as the argument(s) of the function.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
  
  
    <entry>
      
      <title type="html">[ADDR2] 1-Bit Full Adder</title>
      
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/02/06/pset-addr2/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="[ADDR2] 1-Bit Full Adder" />
      <published>2018-02-06T14:30:08+05:30</published>
      <updated>2018-02-06T14:30:08+05:30</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/2018/02/06/pset-addr2</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/02/06/pset-addr2/">&lt;p&gt;Design 1-bit full adder using the minimum number of logic gates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-are-adders&quot;&gt;What are adders?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An adder is a digital circuit that performs addition of numbers. In many computers and other kinds of processors adders are used in the arithmetic logic units or ALU. They are also utilized in other parts of the processor, where they are used to calculate addresses, table indices, increment and decrement operators, and similar operations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;half-adders-vs-full-adders&quot;&gt;Half Adders vs Full Adders&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The half adder adds two single binary digits A and B. It has two outputs, sum $S$ and carry $C$. The carry signal represents an overflow into the next digit of a multi-digit addition. The value of the sum in decimal system is $2C + S$. The simplest half-adder design, pictured on the right, incorporates an XOR gate for $S$ and an AND gate for $C$. The Boolean logic for the sum (in this case $S$) will be $A’B+AB’$ whereas for carry $C$ will be $AB$. With the addition of an OR gate to combine their carry outputs, two half adders can be combined to make a full adder. The half adder adds two input bits and generates a carry and sum, which are the two outputs of a half adder. The input variables of a half adder are called the augend and addend bits. The output variables are the sum and carry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A full adder adds binary numbers and accounts for values carried in as well as out. A one-bit full-adder adds three one-bit numbers, often written as $A$, $B$, and $C_{in}$; $A$ and $B$ are the operands, and $C_{in}$ is a bit carried in from the previous less-significant stage. The full adder is usually a component in a cascade of adders, which add 8, 16, 32, etc. bit binary numbers. The circuit produces a two-bit output. Output carry and sum typically represented by the signals $C_{out}$ and $S$, where $ sum = 2 C_{out} + S $ in the decimal system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;$A$&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;$B$&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;$C_{in}$&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;$C_{out}$&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;$S$&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      
        <author>
            <name>Gaurav Singh</name>
          
          
        </author>
      

      
        <category term="Pset" />
      
        <category term="1-Point" />
      

      
        <category term="Logic-Gates" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">Design 1-bit full adder using the minimum number of logic gates.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
  
  
    <entry>
      
      <title type="html">[WAVE1] Sine Wave</title>
      
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/02/05/pset-wave/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="[WAVE1] Sine Wave" />
      <published>2018-02-05T14:30:08+05:30</published>
      <updated>2018-02-05T14:30:08+05:30</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/2018/02/05/pset-wave</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/02/05/pset-wave/">&lt;p&gt;Plot sine wave in P5JS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A sine wave or sinusoid is a mathematical curve that describes a smooth repetitive oscillation. A sine wave is a continuous wave. It is named after the function sine, of which it is the graph.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It occurs often in pure and applied mathematics, as well as physics, engineering, signal processing and many other fields. Its most basic form as a function of time $t$ is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;$y(t) = A\sin(2 \pi f t + \phi) = A\sin(\omega t + \phi)$&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;where:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;$A$ = the amplitude, the peak deviation of the function from zero.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;$f$ = the ordinary frequency, the number of oscillations (cycles) that occur each second of time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;$\omega = 2 \pi f$, the angular frequency, the rate of change of the function argument in units of radians per second&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;$\phi$ = the phase specifies (in radians) wherein its cycle the oscillation is at $t = 0$.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When $\phi$ is non-zero, the entire waveform appears to be shifted in time by the amount $\frac{\phi}{\omega}$ seconds. A negative value represents a delay, and a positive value represents an advance.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      
        <author>
            <name>Gaurav Singh</name>
          
          
        </author>
      

      
        <category term="Pset" />
      
        <category term="1-Point" />
      

      
        <category term="p5.js" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">Plot sine wave in P5JS.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
  
  
    <entry>
      
      <title type="html">[PROJ3] Simulating Projectile Motion</title>
      
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/02/04/pset-proj3/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="[PROJ3] Simulating Projectile Motion" />
      <published>2018-02-04T14:30:08+05:30</published>
      <updated>2018-02-04T14:30:08+05:30</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/2018/02/04/pset-proj3</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/02/04/pset-proj3/">&lt;p&gt;Read the value of initial velocity $u$ and throwing angle theta from a textbox and simulate simple projectile motion in P5JS.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      
        <author>
            <name>Gaurav Singh</name>
          
          
        </author>
      

      
        <category term="Pset" />
      
        <category term="1-Point" />
      

      
        <category term="Kinematics" />
      
        <category term="p5.js" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">Read the value of initial velocity $u$ and throwing angle theta from a textbox and simulate simple projectile motion in P5JS.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
  
  
    <entry>
      
      <title type="html">[LWSC1] Caroll’s Puzzles</title>
      
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/02/04/pset-lwsc1/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="[LWSC1] Caroll's Puzzles" />
      <published>2018-02-04T14:30:08+05:30</published>
      <updated>2018-02-04T14:30:08+05:30</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/2018/02/04/pset-lwsc1</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/02/04/pset-lwsc1/">&lt;p&gt;Lewis Carroll may have exaggerated a little, as math professors often do about the utility of their subject. Carroll is best known for his nonsensical books, including the infamous “Alice in Wonderland”, written for children of ages five to ninety; but his main line of work was as a professor of mathematics at Oxford University in England. He studied logic as a vocation, and he played with logic in his writings. His stories of little girls and strange creatures are filled with bad puns and other plays with words, absurd implications, contradictions, and numerous and various offenses to common sense. It is as though he were writing his silly stories as much to amuse himself as to entertain his audiences. As a teacher of logic and a lover of nonsense, Carroll designed entertaining puzzles to train people in systematic reasoning. In these puzzles he strings together a list of implications, purposefully inane so that the reader is not influenced by any preconceived opinions. The job of the reader is to use all the listed implications to arrive at an inescapable conclusion. You will get the general idea after the following example.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Example:
(a)  All babies are illogical.&lt;br /&gt;
(b)  Nobody is despised who can manage a crocodile.&lt;br /&gt;
(c)  Illogical persons are despised.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Solution:&lt;br /&gt;
As the subjects of this puzzle are people, we take the universe as the set of all people. We will rewrite each statement in the puzzle as an implication. First, we define simpler statements,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;B: it is a baby&lt;br /&gt;
L: it is logical&lt;br /&gt;
M: it can manage a crocodile&lt;br /&gt;
D: it is despised,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;where “it” in this context refers to a general person. Then the three statements can be rephrased as&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;B → ~ L : If it is a baby then it is not logical.&lt;br /&gt;
M → ~ D : If it can manage a crocodile then it is not despised.&lt;br /&gt;
~L → D : If it is not logical then it is despised.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our aim is to use transitive reasoning several times, stringing together a chain of implications using all the given statements. We have an arrow pointing from B to ~L, and likewise an arrow pointing from ~L to D; thus we are able to start with B and arrive at the conclusion D. However, the second statement is still not utilized. But since any implication is equivalent to its contrapositive, we may replace the second statement with its contrapositive D → ~M. Then we get the transitive reasoning chain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;B → ~L → D → ~M&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We reason that if B is true, then ~L is true, hence D is true, and therefore ~M is true. Our ultimate conclusion is the statement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;B → ~ M: If it is a baby then it cannot manage a crocodile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In ordinary language, we would more likely rephrase this answer to the puzzle as&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“No baby can manage a crocodile.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alternatively, we could write the answer as the contrapositive statement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;M → ~ B: If it can manage a crocodile then it is not a baby.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The translation of words then would be something like&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Anyone who can manage a crocodile is not a baby.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lewis Carroll created these puzzles. In each puzzle, you are to write the assertions symbolically as implications, along with their contrapositives, and then string together with arrows all the assertions to arrive at a final conclusion. Your answer will be an ultimate implication, which you must then cleverly translate back into ordinary language.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(a) My saucepans are the only things I have that are made of tin. &lt;br /&gt;
I find all your presents very useful. &lt;br /&gt;
None of my saucepans are of the slightest use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(b) All writers, who understand human nature, are clever. &lt;br /&gt;
No one is a true poet unless he can stir the hearts of men. &lt;br /&gt;
Shakespeare wrote “Hamlet”. &lt;br /&gt;
No writer, who does not understand human nature, can stir the hearts of men.&lt;br /&gt;
 None but a true poet could have written “Hamlet”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(c) I despise anything that cannot be used as a bridge. &lt;br /&gt;
Everything, that is worth writing an ode to, would be a welcome gift to me. &lt;br /&gt;
A rainbow will not bear the weight of a wheelbarrow.&lt;br /&gt;
 Whatever can be used as a bridge will bear the weight of a wheelbarrow.&lt;br /&gt;
 I would not take, as a gift, a thing that I despise.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      
        <author>
            <name>Gaurav Singh</name>
          
          
        </author>
      

      
        <category term="Pset" />
      
        <category term="1-Point" />
      

      
        <category term="Propositional-Logic" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">Lewis Carroll may have exaggerated a little, as math professors often do about the utility of their subject. Carroll is best known for his nonsensical books, including the infamous “Alice in Wonderland”, written for children of ages five to ninety; but his main line of work was as a professor of mathematics at Oxford University in England. He studied logic as a vocation, and he played with logic in his writings. His stories of little girls and strange creatures are filled with bad puns and other plays with words, absurd implications, contradictions, and numerous and various offenses to common sense. It is as though he were writing his silly stories as much to amuse himself as to entertain his audiences. As a teacher of logic and a lover of nonsense, Carroll designed entertaining puzzles to train people in systematic reasoning. In these puzzles he strings together a list of implications, purposefully inane so that the reader is not influenced by any preconceived opinions. The job of the reader is to use all the listed implications to arrive at an inescapable conclusion. You will get the general idea after the following example.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
  
  
    <entry>
      
      <title type="html">[ELLIP] Elliptical Orbit</title>
      
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/02/03/pset-ellip/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="[ELLIP] Elliptical Orbit" />
      <published>2018-02-03T14:30:08+05:30</published>
      <updated>2018-02-03T14:30:08+05:30</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/2018/02/03/pset-ellip</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/02/03/pset-ellip/">&lt;p&gt;Simulate a 2-body system where one body (ball) is fixed at the center of the canvas while the other rotates around it in a highly elliptical path.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      
        <author>
            <name>Gaurav Singh</name>
          
          
        </author>
      

      
        <category term="Pset" />
      
        <category term="1-Point" />
      

      
        <category term="Kinematics" />
      
        <category term="p5.js" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">Simulate a 2-body system where one body (ball) is fixed at the center of the canvas while the other rotates around it in a highly elliptical path.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
  
  
    <entry>
      
      <title type="html">[SUBR1] 1-Bit Half Subtractor</title>
      
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/02/02/pset-subr1/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="[SUBR1] 1-Bit Half Subtractor" />
      <published>2018-02-02T14:30:08+05:30</published>
      <updated>2018-02-02T14:30:08+05:30</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/2018/02/02/pset-subr1</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/02/02/pset-subr1/">&lt;p&gt;Design 1-bit half subtractor using the minimum number of logic gates. The half-subtractor is a combinational circuit which is used to perform subtraction of two bits. It has two inputs, $X$ (minuend) and $Y$ (subtrahend) and two outputs $D$ (difference) and $B$ (borrow).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;A&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;B&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;C&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;S&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      
        <author>
            <name>Gaurav Singh</name>
          
          
        </author>
      

      
        <category term="Pset" />
      
        <category term="1-Point" />
      

      
        <category term="Logic-Gates" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">Design 1-bit half subtractor using the minimum number of logic gates. The half-subtractor is a combinational circuit which is used to perform subtraction of two bits. It has two inputs, $X$ (minuend) and $Y$ (subtrahend) and two outputs $D$ (difference) and $B$ (borrow).</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
  
  
    <entry>
      
      <title type="html">[BALL2] Crossing Balls</title>
      
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/02/02/pset-ball2/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="[BALL2] Crossing Balls" />
      <published>2018-02-02T14:30:08+05:30</published>
      <updated>2018-02-02T14:30:08+05:30</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/2018/02/02/pset-ball2</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/02/02/pset-ball2/">&lt;p&gt;In P5JS, write a program that shows a ball moving towards the right, between left and right bounds of the canvas, and another ball moving in opposite direction. Given: Both balls are moving at the same velocity. Ball A and Ball B start at an exact same time from opposite bounds in a canvas of size 600x400 pixels.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      
        <author>
            <name>Gaurav Singh</name>
          
          
        </author>
      

      
        <category term="Pset" />
      
        <category term="1-Point" />
      

      
        <category term="Kinematics" />
      
        <category term="p5.js" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">In P5JS, write a program that shows a ball moving towards the right, between left and right bounds of the canvas, and another ball moving in opposite direction. Given: Both balls are moving at the same velocity. Ball A and Ball B start at an exact same time from opposite bounds in a canvas of size 600x400 pixels.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
  
  
    <entry>
      
      <title type="html">[PROJ1] Standard Projectile motion</title>
      
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/02/01/pset-proj1/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="[PROJ1] Standard Projectile motion" />
      <published>2018-02-01T14:30:08+05:30</published>
      <updated>2018-02-01T14:30:08+05:30</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/2018/02/01/pset-proj1</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/02/01/pset-proj1/">&lt;p&gt;Given that an object is launched at an initial velocity $v$ with an angle from the horizontal in vacuum system placed on Earth. Gravity is experienced only downwards and may be represented by $a_g$. Derive the following kinematic quantities of a standard projectile motion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;$a$, Acceleration at any time $t$&lt;br /&gt;
$v$, Velocity at any time $t$&lt;br /&gt;
$x$ and $y$, Displacement at any time $t$&lt;br /&gt;
$T$, Total time of flight&lt;br /&gt;
$h$, Maximum height of the projectile&lt;br /&gt;
$d$, Maximum distance of the projectile&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      
        <author>
            <name>Gaurav Singh</name>
          
          
        </author>
      

      
        <category term="Pset" />
      
        <category term="1-Point" />
      

      
        <category term="Physics" />
      
        <category term="Kinematics" />
      
        <category term="p5.js" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">Given that an object is launched at an initial velocity $v$ with an angle from the horizontal in vacuum system placed on Earth. Gravity is experienced only downwards and may be represented by $a_g$. Derive the following kinematic quantities of a standard projectile motion.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
  
  
    <entry>
      
      <title type="html">[CIRCL] Circular Motion</title>
      
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/02/01/pset-circl/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="[CIRCL] Circular Motion" />
      <published>2018-02-01T14:30:08+05:30</published>
      <updated>2018-02-01T14:30:08+05:30</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/2018/02/01/pset-circl</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/02/01/pset-circl/">&lt;p&gt;Animate a ball to move in circular motion in P5JS.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      
        <author>
            <name>Gaurav Singh</name>
          
          
        </author>
      

      
        <category term="Pset" />
      
        <category term="1-Point" />
      

      
        <category term="Physics" />
      
        <category term="Kinematics" />
      
        <category term="p5.js" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">Animate a ball to move in circular motion in P5JS.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
  
</feed>
