<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.7.3">Jekyll</generator>
  
  
  <link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
  <link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
  <updated>2018-03-28T01:09:55+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://localhost:4000//</id>

  
    <title type="html">DecodeVector</title>
  

  

  
    <author>
        <name>Mathscapes Research</name>
      
      
    </author>
  

  
  
    <entry>
      
      <title type="html">Introduction to Python</title>
      
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/03/28/introduction-to-python/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Introduction to Python" />
      <published>2018-03-28T00:04:08+05:30</published>
      <updated>2018-03-28T00:04:08+05:30</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/2018/03/28/introduction-to-python</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/03/28/introduction-to-python/">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.python.org/downloads/&quot;&gt;Download Python&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://python.swaroopch.com/&quot;&gt;A Byte of Python&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.python.org/3/&quot;&gt;Python Official Documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      
        <author>
            <name>Gaurav Singh</name>
          
          
        </author>
      

      
        <category term="Resources" />
      

      
        <category term="Python" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">Download Python A Byte of Python Python Official Documentation</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
  
  
    <entry>
      
      <title type="html">Getting Started with p5.js</title>
      
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/03/28/getting-started-with-p5js/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Getting Started with p5.js" />
      <published>2018-03-28T00:04:08+05:30</published>
      <updated>2018-03-28T00:04:08+05:30</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/2018/03/28/getting-started-with-p5js</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/03/28/getting-started-with-p5js/">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://p5js.org/get-started/&quot;&gt;Get Started&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://p5js.org/download/&quot;&gt;Download p5.js Library&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://p5js.org/reference/&quot;&gt;Reference&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      
        <author>
            <name>Gaurav Singh</name>
          
          
        </author>
      

      
        <category term="Resources" />
      

      
        <category term="p5.js" />
      
        <category term="Processing" />
      
        <category term="JavaScript" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">Get Started Download p5.js Library Reference</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
  
  
    <entry>
      
      <title type="html">Using GitHub</title>
      
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/03/27/using-github/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Using GitHub" />
      <published>2018-03-27T16:20:08+05:30</published>
      <updated>2018-03-27T16:20:08+05:30</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/2018/03/27/using-github</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/03/27/using-github/">&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-is-github&quot;&gt;What is GitHub?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=w3jLJU7DT5E&quot;&gt;What is GitHub? &lt;em&gt;(Video)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;getting-started&quot;&gt;Getting Started&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://try.github.io/levels/1/challenges/1&quot;&gt;Using GitHub&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://guides.github.com/introduction/flow/&quot;&gt;Understanding the GitHub Flow&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://guides.github.com/activities/hello-world/&quot;&gt;Hello World&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;more&quot;&gt;More&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://guides.github.com/features/issues/&quot;&gt;Mastering Issues&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://guides.github.com/features/mastering-markdown/&quot;&gt;Mastering Markdown&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      
        <author>
            <name>Gaurav Singh</name>
          
          
        </author>
      

      
        <category term="Resources" />
      

      
        <category term="GitHub" />
      
        <category term="Git" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">What is GitHub? What is GitHub? (Video)</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
  
  
    <entry>
      
      <title type="html">Contributing to this website</title>
      
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/03/27/contributing-to-this-website/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Contributing to this website" />
      <published>2018-03-27T12:04:08+05:30</published>
      <updated>2018-03-27T12:04:08+05:30</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/2018/03/27/contributing-to-this-website</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/03/27/contributing-to-this-website/">&lt;p&gt;Send your posts (in .markdown format) to &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:grv@mathscapes.xyz&quot;&gt;me&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;formatting-guide&quot;&gt;Formatting Guide&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://guides.github.com/features/mastering-markdown/&quot;&gt;Mastering Markdown&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://moser-isi.ethz.ch/docs/typeset_equations.pdf&quot;&gt;Typesetting Equations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In case of any queries, create a issue &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mathscapes/DecodeVector/issues&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      
        <author>
            <name>Gaurav Singh</name>
          
          
        </author>
      

      
        <category term="Important" />
      

      
        <category term="Markdown" />
      
        <category term="Latex" />
      
        <category term="Math" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">Send your posts (in .markdown format) to me.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
  
  
    <entry>
      
      <title type="html">Code of Conduct</title>
      
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/03/27/code-of-conduct/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Code of Conduct" />
      <published>2018-03-27T12:04:08+05:30</published>
      <updated>2018-03-27T12:04:08+05:30</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/2018/03/27/code-of-conduct</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/03/27/code-of-conduct/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;big&gt;This Code is not exhaustive or complete. It is not a rulebook; it serves to distil our common understanding of a collaborative, shared environment and goals. We expect it to be followed in spirit as much as in this document.&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This code of conduct outlines our expectations for participants within the DecodeVector community, as well as steps to reporting unacceptable behavior. We are committed to providing a welcoming and inspiring community for all and expect our code of conduct to be honored. Anyone who violates this code of conduct may be banned from the community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Morality cannot be legislated, but behavior can be regulated.
– Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;our-decodevector-community-strives-to&quot;&gt;Our DecodeVector community strives to:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Be friendly and patient.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Be welcoming:&lt;/em&gt; We strive to be a community that welcomes and supports people of all backgrounds and identities. This includes, but is not limited to members of any race, ethnicity, culture, national origin, colour, immigration status, social and economic class, educational level, sex, sexual orientation, gender identity and expression, age, size, family status, political belief, religion, and mental and physical ability.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Be considerate:&lt;/em&gt; Your work will be used by other people, and you in turn will depend on the work of others. Any decision you take will affect other members, and you should take those consequences into account when making decisions.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Be respectful:&lt;/em&gt; Not all of us will agree all the time, but disagreement is no excuse for poor behavior and poor manners. We might all experience some frustration now and then, but we cannot allow that frustration to turn into a personal attack. It’s important to remember that a community where people feel uncomfortable or threatened is not a productive one.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Be careful in the words that we choose:&lt;/em&gt; we are a community of professionals, and we conduct ourselves professionally. Be kind to others. Do not insult or put down other members. Harassment and other exclusionary behavior aren’t acceptable.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Try to understand why we disagree:&lt;/em&gt; Disagreements, both social and technical, happen all the time. It is important that we resolve disagreements and differing views constructively. Remember that we’re different. The strength of our community comes from its diversity, people from a wide range of backgrounds. Different people have different perspectives on issues. Being unable to understand why someone holds a viewpoint doesn’t mean that they’re wrong. Don’t forget that it is human to err and blaming each other doesn’t get us anywhere. Instead, focus on helping to resolve issues and learning from mistakes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;leadership-authority-and-responsibility&quot;&gt;Leadership, authority and responsibility&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We all lead by example, in debate and in action. We encourage new members to feel empowered to lead, to take action, and to experiment when they feel innovation could improve the project. Leadership can be exercised by anyone simply by taking action, there is no need to wait for recognition when the opportunity to lead presents itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;delegation-from-the-top&quot;&gt;Delegation from the top&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Responsibility within DecodeVector starts with the “benevolent dictator”, who delegates specific responsibilities and the corresponding authority to a series of teams. Its delegated representative will arbitrate in any dispute.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We are a meritocracy&lt;/strong&gt;; we delegate decision making, organisation and leadership from senior bodies to the most able and engaged candidates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;we-value-discussion-data-and-decisiveness&quot;&gt;We value discussion, data and decisiveness&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We gather opinions, data and commitments from concerned parties before taking a decision. We expect leaders to help teams come to a decision in a reasonable time, to seek guidance or be willing to take the decision themselves when consensus is lacking, and to take responsibility for implementation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The poorest decision of all is no decision: clarity of direction has value in itself. Sometimes all the data are not available, or consensus is elusive. A decision must still be made. There is no guarantee of a perfect decision every time - we prefer to err, learn, and err less in future than to postpone action indefinitely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We recognise that the project works better when we trust the teams closest to a problem to make the decision for the project. If we learn of a decision that we disagree with, we can engage the relevant team to find common ground, and failing that, we have a governance structure that can review the decision. Ultimately, if a decision has been taken by the people responsible for it, and is supported by the DecodeVector, it will stand. None of us expects to agree with every decision, and we value highly the willingness to stand by the project and help it deliver even on the occasions when we ourselves may prefer a different route.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;teamwork&quot;&gt;Teamwork&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A leader’s foremost goal is the success of the team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“A virtuoso is judged by their actions; a leader is judged by the actions of their team.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A leader knows when to act and when to step back. They know when to delegate work, and when to take it upon themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;credit&quot;&gt;Credit&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A good leader does not seek the limelight, but celebrates team members for the work they do. Leaders may be more visible than members of the team, good ones use that visibility to highlight the great work of others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;courage-and-considerateness&quot;&gt;Courage and considerateness&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leadership occasionally requires bold decisions that will not be widely understood, agreed by everyone or popular. We value the courage to take such decisions, because they enable the DecodeVector as a whole to move forward faster than we could if we required complete consensus. Nevertheless, boldness demands considerateness; take bold decisions, but do so mindful of the challenges they present for others, and work to soften the impact of those decisions on them. Communicating changes and their reasoning clearly and early on is as important as the implementation of the change itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;conflicts-of-interest&quot;&gt;Conflicts of interest&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We expect leaders to be aware when they are conflicted due to personal schedule or other projects they are involved in, and abstain or delegate decisions that may be seen to be self-interested. We expect that everyone who participates in DecodeVector does so with the goal of progress of DecodeVector.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When in doubt, ask for a second opinion. Perceived conflicts of interest are important to address; as a leader, act to ensure that decisions are credible even if they must occasionally be unpopular, difficult or favourable to the interests of one group over another.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;diversity-statement&quot;&gt;Diversity Statement&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We encourage everyone to participate and are committed to building a community for all. Although we will fail at times, we seek to treat everyone both as fairly and equally as possible. Whenever a member has made a mistake, we expect them to take responsibility for it. If someone has been harmed or offended, it is our responsibility to listen carefully and respectfully, and do our best to right the wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although this list cannot be exhaustive, we explicitly honor diversity in age, gender, gender identity or expression, culture, ethnicity, language, national origin, political beliefs, profession, race, religion, sexual orientation, socioeconomic status, and technical ability. We will not tolerate discrimination based on any of the protected characteristics above, including participants with disabilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;attribution--acknowledgements&quot;&gt;Attribution &amp;amp; Acknowledgements&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This document uses portions from &lt;a href=&quot;http://todogroup.org/opencodeofconduct/&quot;&gt;Open Code of Conduct by TODO Group&lt;/a&gt; and is inspired from other communities and projects – &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.djangoproject.com/conduct/reporting/&quot;&gt;Django&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.python.org/community/diversity/&quot;&gt;Python&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ubuntu.com/community/code-of-conduct&quot;&gt;Ubuntu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.contributor-covenant.org/&quot;&gt;Contributor Covenant&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://geekfeminism.org/about/code-of-conduct/&quot;&gt;Geek Feminism&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://citizencodeofconduct.org/&quot;&gt;Citizen Code of Conduct&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our Code of Conduct is licensed under &lt;a href=&quot;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/&quot;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution-Share Alike 3.0 license&lt;/a&gt; and you may re-use it for your own community, and modify it as you wish, just please allow others to use your modifications and give credit to the DecodeVector and all the above organisations/projects!&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      
        <author>
            <name>Gaurav Singh</name>
          
          
        </author>
      

      
        <category term="Important" />
      

      

      
        <summary type="html">This Code is not exhaustive or complete. It is not a rulebook; it serves to distil our common understanding of a collaborative, shared environment and goals. We expect it to be followed in spirit as much as in this document.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
  
</feed>
